<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Roberto Allende</title><description>AI-first engineering leader, builder, and football coach based in New Zealand. Notes on technology, leadership, learning, and the work in between.</description><link>https://allende.nz/</link><item><title>[Software] Build and ship an entire app using Amazon Q</title><link>https://community.aws/content/32oVtOpyI0e0YSI9H4kLvb5Mlvw</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://community.aws/content/32oVtOpyI0e0YSI9H4kLvb5Mlvw</guid><description>How the AWS Lambda Hackathon let me stress test an idea that ended up transforming how I work with Q CLI to develop software.

This post is based on a presentation at AWS Community Day 2025, New Zealand, Aotearoa.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:14:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Software] Not a portfolio. Not a blog. A conversation</title><link>https://community.aws/content/2yxKHol9N5tba3Uju1eRcHUymSm</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://community.aws/content/2yxKHol9N5tba3Uju1eRcHUymSm</guid><description>A few days ago, I came across the AWS Builder Challenge—and I couldn’t resist. 

I love these sprints: the adrenaline of a deadline, the chance to challenge assumptions, and the opportunity to try and learn something new.</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 14:26:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Software] Code with AI: Micromanagement is all you need</title><link>https://community.aws/content/2y6nQgj1FVuaJIn9rFLThIslwaJ</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://community.aws/content/2y6nQgj1FVuaJIn9rFLThIslwaJ</guid><description>Yes, it says micromanagement - and this time it makes sense.</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 14:17:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Software] Five Takeaways from AWS Summit Sydney 2025</title><link>https://community.aws/content/2y6VTiNmyMKGnFslikzXkfecPd9</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://community.aws/content/2y6VTiNmyMKGnFslikzXkfecPd9</guid><description>June 4-5, 2025 saw AWS bring together thousands of developers, builders, and business leaders at Sydney&apos;s International Convention Centre for their annual Summit. Across 90+ sessions and 80+ partner showcases, the event highlighted both where AWS is directing their efforts and how customers are putting those tools to work Amazon— here are five things that stood out to me from the two days.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 04:02:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Software] AI First Imperative: What Does It Mean to Be AI First</title><link>https://community.aws/content/2uTxBHfOqBru2fkVYGFg1023pXp</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://community.aws/content/2uTxBHfOqBru2fkVYGFg1023pXp</guid><description>I’ve been practicing an AI First mindset for a few months now. It wasn’t something I defined from the start—it just emerged naturally from how I worked. Whether I was tackling a complex project, debugging a technical issue, or drafting a message, AI became a central part of my thinking loop.</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 07:42:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Football] Bielsa: &quot;Don&apos;t Let Failure Lower Your Self-Esteem&quot;</title><link>https://en.allende.nz/football/bielsa-dont-let-failure-lower-your-self-esteem/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.allende.nz/football/bielsa-dont-let-failure-lower-your-self-esteem/</guid><description>The following is a translation of the article published in Marca.com in May 2012. Photo by Bruce Rollinson, taken after Leeds United’s loss at Queens Park Rangers on 26 February 2019. The Athletic coach made it clear years ago in a talk with young people...</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 22:39:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Football] Adversity in Football and in Life</title><link>https://en.allende.nz/football/overcoming-adversity-in-football/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.allende.nz/football/overcoming-adversity-in-football/</guid><description>When I was 10 years old, I wanted to play football and I joined a club. My friends suggested I should be a goalkeeper because they thought I had the skills and the team only had one who apparently did not stand out. However, in the first practice, I chose to play as a defender, which led to a resounding &quot;No!&quot; from my friends. I wanted to be number two, a position already held by the team&apos;s captain, an irreplaceable player.</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 05:33:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Football] Beyond the Joystick. Empowering Players&apos; Autonomy and Creativity in Football</title><link>https://en.allende.nz/football/beyond-the-joystick-empowering-players-autonomy-and-creativity-in-football/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.allende.nz/football/beyond-the-joystick-empowering-players-autonomy-and-creativity-in-football/</guid><description>How can we prevent all players from crowding around the ball like a swarm of bees? That was one of the first questions I asked myself when I started coaching kids.
I don’t know if there’s a perfect solution, and I’m still searching for an answer to that question. I keep searching because, in reality, this is part of a broader problem that doesn’t only apply to kids. It’s about influencing the behavior of a group or even shaping habits.
Here are two different alternatives to solve this problem.</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Football] Fast! Play fast</title><link>https://en.allende.nz/football/fast-play-fast/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.allende.nz/football/fast-play-fast/</guid><description>Playing slowly allows your opponent to get organized, which often leads to turnovers and ultimately, losses. Avoiding slow play is crucial for winning games. So, what does it mean to play fast? Watch the following video to see fast football in action: Playing fast in...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Football] Introducing Astuten</title><link>https://en.allende.nz/football/introducing-astuten/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.allende.nz/football/introducing-astuten/</guid><description>As a grassroots football coach I want to make sure I give fair playing time to every player on my team. That’s why I used to spend hours planning game subs. Planning subs is not easy because it’s not just about playing time. You also...</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>