<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Roberto Allende</title><description>AI-first engineering leader, builder, and football coach based in New Zealand. Notes on technology, leadership, learning, and the work in between.</description><link>https://allende.nz/</link><item><title>[Software] Find new AWS Builder articles on X</title><link>https://community.aws/content/38YlMSH2Yy2WCd2iNOVfUZZcMYC</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://community.aws/content/38YlMSH2Yy2WCd2iNOVfUZZcMYC</guid><description>uAWSBuilderFeed is an unofficial automated feed that republishes AWS Builder articles to X.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:35:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Software] Build and ship an entire app using Amazon Q</title><link>https://community.aws/content/32oVtOpyI0e0YSI9H4kLvb5Mlvw</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://community.aws/content/32oVtOpyI0e0YSI9H4kLvb5Mlvw</guid><description>How the AWS Lambda Hackathon let me stress test an idea that ended up transforming how I work with Q CLI to develop software.

This post is based on a presentation at AWS Community Day 2025, New Zealand, Aotearoa.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:14:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Software] Not a portfolio. Not a blog. A conversation</title><link>https://community.aws/content/2yxKHol9N5tba3Uju1eRcHUymSm</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://community.aws/content/2yxKHol9N5tba3Uju1eRcHUymSm</guid><description>A few days ago, I came across the AWS Builder Challenge—and I couldn’t resist. 

I love these sprints: the adrenaline of a deadline, the chance to challenge assumptions, and the opportunity to try and learn something new.</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 14:26:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Software] Code with AI: Micromanagement is all you need</title><link>https://community.aws/content/2y6nQgj1FVuaJIn9rFLThIslwaJ</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://community.aws/content/2y6nQgj1FVuaJIn9rFLThIslwaJ</guid><description>Yes, it says micromanagement - and this time it makes sense.</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 14:17:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Software] Five Takeaways from AWS Summit Sydney 2025</title><link>https://community.aws/content/2y6VTiNmyMKGnFslikzXkfecPd9</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://community.aws/content/2y6VTiNmyMKGnFslikzXkfecPd9</guid><description>June 4-5, 2025 saw AWS bring together thousands of developers, builders, and business leaders at Sydney&apos;s International Convention Centre for their annual Summit. Across 90+ sessions and 80+ partner showcases, the event highlighted both where AWS is directing their efforts and how customers are putting those tools to work Amazon— here are five things that stood out to me from the two days.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 04:02:10 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>